Joe, I don't think a four-letter word
for "ship" can be "ship."
SHIP에 걸리는 네 글자
단어가 어떻게 SHIP이야
I thought it was a freebie.
보너스인 줄 알았네
Hello!
안녕?
What's this?
이게 뭐지?
Oh, right!
It's that girl's phone number.
오호라, 그 여자 전화번호군
There it is.
Just a phone number...
이거 어때, 진짜 새끈한
여자가 준 전화번호야
...a really hot girl gave me.
It's no big deal. I mean,
it is her home phone number, but....
별건 아니지만
집 전화번호거든
와우!
어럽쇼?
Almost lost this baby!
실종될 뻔했네
The lovely Amanda gives me her
number, and I go and drop it.
사랑스런 아만다의 전화번호
그걸 떨어뜨리다니
Thank you.
고마워
The One with
Joey's New Girlfriend
- 레이첼?
- 네?
-When's your birthday?
-May 5th. Why?
생일이 언제지?
- 5월 5일인데, 왜요?
- 혹시나 해서 적어두려고
I'm making a list of birthdays.
-Mine's December
-Yeah, whatever.
- 난 12월...
- 그래, 뭐든
She's pretty!
예쁘다
Pretty, pretty girl. The pretty
She's pretty.
예쁘다, 예뻐
무지 예쁘다고
Go ask her out.
만나자고 해봐
-What's the worst that could happen?
-I could die.
- 잘못될 거 있어?
- 죽으면 어떡해
Yeah, it's tough being single.
그래, 싱글 생활은 힘들지
난 다행히 아만다를 찾았지만
That's why I'm so glad I found Amanda.
Ross, you guys went out once.
딱 한 번 만났잖아
You took your kids to Chuck E. Cheese,
and you didn't even kiss her.
애들이랑 같이 가서
키스도 못했을 텐데
I tell people secrets.
맞아, 나 입 싸다
그래야 날 좋아하니까
It makes them like me.
All I'm gonna say is, finally, it's
nice to be in a mature relationship.
늦었지만 나도 성숙한 관계를
갖게 됐다니 정말 다행스러워
You know, the world would
be such a better place...
그 말만 하고 입 닫으면
세상 참 살기 좋을 텐데
...if that actually was
all you were gonna say.
Phoebe.
피비, 몸이 안 좋으면
집에 가서 쉬어야지
You're sick.
You shouldn't play. Go home.
But I'm unemployed.
지금은 일자리도 없어
남은 건 음악뿐이야
My music is all I really have now.
Well, music and making my own shoes.
Pretty, huh?
내가 만든 신발도 있구나
예쁘지?
All right, I'm gonna do it.
좋아, 해볼게
장렬하게 전사하리라
I'm gonna go get shot down.
Any advice?
- 할말 있나?
- 평소에 하던 대로
Just be yourself...
...but not too much.
너무 심하지 않게
Wish me luck.
행운을 빌어줘
Good luck!
행운을 빈다!
Wish it!
맘속으로!
안녕하세요, 저쪽에서 봤는데...
챈들러입니다, 그거 말했나요?
I was just sitting over there and....
My name's Chandler.
Did I say that?
No, you didn't.
Hi, I'm Kathy.
아뇨, 그럴 리가
전 캐시라고 해요
- 캐시면, K? C?
- K예요
-Kathy with a K or a C?
-With a K.
오호라!
Wow, you are really good at this!
이 방면에 조예가 깊으시네요
I'm out on a limb here!
무슨 말씀, 심장이
다 벌렁거리는데
I'm sorry.
You're right.
네, 죄송한 말씀이지만
데이트 약속이 있어요
But I should tell you,
I'm waiting for a date.
And there he is now!
오! 저기 왔네요
두 사람 벌써 인사했어?
I see you guys already met.
I was trying to demonstrate...
그래, 김칫국 마시다 체했을 때
냉수 마시고 속 차리는 법을
실황중계로 보여주고 있었어
...how I could get my
very large feet...
...into my even bigger mouth.
Didn't I tell you?
내가 뭐랬어
겸손이랑 담 쌓은 친구야
Always showing off.
Before I start, I want to say
that I have a cold.
제가 어쩌다 감기에
걸리고 말았답니다
So if I sneeze during a song,
it's not on purpose.
중간에 재채기를 하더라도
고의는 아니니 이해하세요
Except the last verse of
"Pepper People."
참, 후추 동네 사람들
부분은 빼고요
Smelly cat, smelly cat
냄새나는 고양이
What are they feeding you?
대체 뭘 먹었니
This chick sounds good.
들어줄 만한데요?
Smelly cat
냄새나는 고양이...
건터, 위스키나 갖다 줘요
Gunther, be a good little boy
and bring me a whiskey.
- 이런!
- 나왔어요?
At 2:30 a.m., I didn't expect
to have to fight over the remote.
새벽 2시 반에 리모콘
쟁탈전이 벌어지겠네
Sorry, there's this Ernie Kovacs
thing I wanted to watch.
미안해요, 어니 코박이
나오는 프로그램이라
세상에, 나도 그거 볼 건데
That's why I got up too.
진짜요?
그 사람 너무 좋아요
You're kidding?
I love him!
My dad made me stay up
and watch reruns with him.
아빠는 재방송까지 봤어요
Mine too. Did your dad also make
you watch the Mr. Universe contest?
우리 아버지도, 미스터
유니버스 대회도 보셨죠?
-No.
-Well, me neither.
- 아뇨
- 우리 아버지도
I'm sorry about this afternoon. If I had
known that you two, I never would have....
아까는 미안했어요
진작 알았더라면...
괜찮아요
Oh, please.
Joey tells me you two met
in acting class.
- 연기학교에서 만났다면서요?
- 네, 우린 한 조인데
They teamed us up as partners.
Joey picked three scenes for us to do.
조이가 고른 장면은
다 야한 결말이에요
All of them had us making out.
That's a good thing because he used to
make me rehearse with him.
다행이군요, 전에는
나랑 연습했는데
-ls it on?
-No, but this Wonder Broom is amazing!
- 나와요?
- 저 마술빗자루 끝내줘요
잠깐...
엄마야!
Oh, my God!
It's on!
시작했어요
Here we go, little fella.
이리 오너라
What about the duck?
오리는요?
The duck can swim.
- 쟤는 수영 잘해요
- 내 정신 좀 봐
My sticky shoes
끈끈이 구두야
끈적끈적 구두야
My sticky, sticky shoes
Why you stick on me?
왜 이리 끈적거리니, 내 새끼!
Baby
Thanks for the lights, honey.
조명 고마웠어, 자기
잘했어!
Way to go!
- 목소리 정말 근사하다
- 내가 이렇게 섹시할 줄이야
Your cold makes you sound great.
It's fun.
God, I love how sexy I am!
Kath, we should get going.
We're going to buy hamsters.
캐시, 이러다 늦겠어
햄스터 사야 되는데
햄스터 귀엽지
I love them.
No, it's not like that.
I work for a medical researcher.
그게 아니라 제가 일하는
실험실에서 부탁한 거라
-Well, have fun.
-Okay.
- 재미 보세요
- 네
It's nice that
the medical community...
의료계가 병든 햄스터를
돕는 건 고무적인 현상이지
...is trying to help sick hamsters.
-lsn't it?
-Yeah, it's great.
그래, 동감이야
You know what?
I like Kathy.
난 캐시가 좋아
- 나도, 활달하고 예쁘고
- 맞아
Me too!
She's so cool and pretty.
She is.
똑똑하고 재미있어
She's smart and funny.
We were up all last night talking.
She said the funniest thing about
어제도 밤새 얘기했는데
얼마나 웃기던지... 뭐?
What?
You love her.
사랑하는구나?
No, I don't.
아냐
Yes, you do.
Chandler loves Kathy.
맞아, 챈들러는
캐시를 사랑한대
-Come on, just lay off him.
-Thank you.
- 피비, 챈들러 괴롭히지 마
- 고맙다, 로스
사랑에 빠져서
좀 예민하거든
He's a little sensitive right now
because he's so in love!
All right.
됐어
오, 캐시!
Kathy, I love you!
캐시, 사랑해!
지금 내 목소리에 맞는
우울한 곡을 쓰고 싶은데
I need to write some depressing stuff
to go with my new bluesy voice.
But nothing that sad has
ever really happened to me.
그런 경험이 통 없어서
엄마의 죽음은 어때?
14살 때 거리를 헤매던 기억은?
How about your mom dying?
Or having to live on the streets
when you were 14?
I could write about the time
my hair did that whoo-hoo thing.
그래! 헤어스타일
망가졌던 때가 있었지?
- 안녕
- 어서 와
I'm going over to Amanda's tonight.
오늘 아만다 집에 가는데
Rachel's not here.
- 레이첼 없어
- 이런...
How's it going with her?
잘 돼가?
Great, actually. I'm thinking
tonight may be the night.
아주 좋아, 오늘이
바로 그 날이 될 거야
The kids are gonna play together,
and then when they're asleep...
애들이 놀다 잠들면
...I'm thinking Amanda and I break
open a bottle of wine...
우린 와인 한 병을 따서
어른들의 놀이를 시작해야지
...do a little playing ourselves.
Hi, guys! This is Josh.
안녕, 얘들아?
이쪽은 조시
Josh, these are my friends.
내 친구들이야
And that's Ross.
저 인간은 로스
- 조시?
- 안녕
Dudes.
방가
You played in college?
대학 때 운동했어요?
I still do.
Next year, I hope to make varsity.
지금도 해요, 내년에
대표팀에 끼고 싶어요
Didn't you play soccer
in high school?
로스? 너도 고교 때
축구하지 않았어?
아니, 경기 일정
잡는 일만 했구나
No, wait. You just organized
their game schedules on your Commodore 64.
It's getting late. I gotta get
to the game, so I'm gonna...head.
전 게임이 있어서
이만... 안뇽
그래
I'll miss you.
- 보고 싶을 거야
- 짱이다!
Dope!
Wow! Cute one.
- 정말 귀엽다
- 아주 깜찍해
-Very cute.
-I know. Isn't he great?
누가 아니래? 이제야
잼나는 관계를 갖게 됐어
So nice to finally be in a
fun relationship, you know?
There's nothing boring about him.
따분하지도 않고
박물관 근처에도 안 가
I bet he's never set foot
in a museum.
Maybe he'll get to go soon.
곧 가게 될 걸?
견학수업 차원에서
Like on a class trip or something.
You know what else is
great about him?
또 좋은 게 뭔지 알아?
What is the word for an adult...
침실에 공룡인형도 없거든
...who doesn't have dinosaur
toys in their bedroom?
오...
What was that?
그게 뭐야?
Monica knows.
모니카가 알지
It's this dumb thing that Ross made up
to try to fool our parents.
엄마 아빠 속이려고
오빠가 만들어낸 거야
It's a way of giving the finger
without actually having to give it.
일종의 욕이라고 생각하면 돼
I cried the night you made that up.
그걸 처음 보고
감격의 눈물을 흘렸어
It was the first time I realized
I was cooler than my big brother.
내가 오빠보다 낫다는 걸
깨달은 날이거든
I'm going to go get ready...
난 외출 준비한다
...for my date tonight...
데이트가 있어서
그럼, 나도 안뇽
...so I'll just "head."
I should go too.
I'm playing in one hour.
나도 가볼게
한 시간 뒤에 공연이 있어
얘들아
You guys should come hear me.
너희들도 와, 오?
이게 왜?
Hear me.
My sticky shoes
끈끈이 구두야
에휴! 에휴!
I lost my sexy phlegm!
섹시한 가래가 없어졌어
- 안녕?
- 왔니, 벤?
Hi, Ben.
-You look great!
-Thanks.
- 정말 예쁜데요?
- 고마워요
어디 보자
안녕, 토미?
Hey, Tommy!
I am so glad that you
could come over tonight.
와줘서 정말 고마워요
Oh, no. It's my pleasure.
무슨 말씀
오히려 저의 영광이죠
My cell phone number
is here on the counter.
내 휴대폰 번호는 적어놨고
먹을 거는 냉장고에 있어요
Please, help yourself to
anything in the fridge.
I appreciate this so much. I have
been trying to go out with...
한 달이나 기다려 온
데이트인데 정말 고마워요
...this guy for a month.
저기...
I'd really appreciate it if you'd
wait and drink your wine...
와인은 애들이 잠든 후에
마셨으면 좋겠어요
...after the kids are asleep.
잘 자라
I blocked the adult channels for the other
babysitters, but the code is four, three
혹시나 해서 채널을 잠가놨는데
암호는 403...
I'm fine.
전 괜찮아요
Thanks for this. I hope I can do
the same for you sometime.
정말 고마워요
신세진 건 꼭 갚을게요
Who wants to make
some long-distance calls?
시외전화 걸 사람?
Kathy!
Kathy! Hi!
캐시! 캐시! 이봐요!
캐시! 캐시!
Kathy!
캐시!
Fetch!
Fetch it!
캐시!
Kathy!
캐시...
이런, 챈들러
여기서 뭐해요?
Chandler, what are you doing here?
I just wanted to say, "Hey!"
반가워서 인사나 하려고
Hey.
반갑네요
Okay.
네, 근데...
You're making it sound
worse than it was.
괜히 부풀릴 거 없어
Her date tipped me $10!
애인이란 작자한테
팁 10달러까지 받았다
What are you doing?
피비, 왜 그래?
I want to be sexy again,
so I'm trying to catch a cold.
섹시함을 되찾으려면
감기에 걸려야 돼
Should be easy.
They're pretty common.
흔한 병이니까 쉽겠지?
You'll catch pneumonia!
그러다 폐렴 걸려
Okay, you were right.
I'm in love with Joey's girlfriend.
너희들이 맞았어
조이의 여자친구가 좋아
- 뭐?
- 진심이야?
-What?
-Are you serious?
잘 알지도 못하면서
어떻게 그런 일이
How is that possible?
You barely know her.
I don't know. I just
모르겠어... 그 여자
생각이 떠나질 않아
I can't get her out of my head.
I'm a very bad person.
I'm a very, very bad person.
난 정말 치사하고 비열하고
질 나쁜 인간 말종이야
I'm a horrible person.
"No, you're not.
We still love you, Chandler!"
이쯤해서 아니라고 해줘야지
Phoebe, I think I caught your cold.
- 너한테 감기 옮았나 봐
- 훔쳐갔다고 하시지?
You mean you stole it!
Don't cover your mouth
when you do that!
입 가리고 하지 마!
We were just talking about you.
챈들러 얘기를 했는데...
Really?
진짜로?
The time you got drunk
and fell asleep...
취해서 변기에 머리 박고
잠든 적 있지?
...with your head in the toilet.
꼭 맞더라
Right in there!
-What movie did you get?
-I got what I always get.
무슨 영화야?
늘 보던 거
'다이 하드'
Die Hard.
- 오우...
- 아니에요
That's what I like about Joey.
Any other guy would have been:
난 이래서 조이뿐이에요
다른 남자들은 '잉글리시
페이션트'도 좋다고 하지만
"Yeah, The English Patient
is my favorite movie too."
But Joey goes, "No way.
Let's get Die Hard.
조이는 이렇게 나오죠
'천만에, 다이 하드야! '
I'm not watching that English crap."
'잉글리시 개똥을 왜 봐'
네, 꿈속의 남자죠
Yeah, he's dreamy.
I gotta go.
I gotta go meet some friends.
난 갈래
친구 놈들 만나러
He has other friends?
딴 친구도 있냐?
Ninety-nine...
99, 100
이제 찾으러 간다!
...a hundred.
Ready or not, here I come!
Let's go over the concept
one more time.
이 놀이의 개념에 대해
다시 한 번 복습하자
- 나야
- 그래
You want to get some dinner
with me and Kathy tonight?
오늘 별일 없으면
캐시랑 같이 저녁 먹자
난 벌써 먹었어
You know what?
I already ate.
It's 4:30.
4시 반인데?
I had a big meal on Monday.
월요일에 거하게 먹었거든
그거면 일주일은 거뜬히 버텨
So that'll get me
straight through the week.
I see what's going on here.
그래, 대충 알겠다
-You do?
-Yeah.
- 알다니?
- 맞아, 캐시가 싫은 거지?
You don't like Kathy.
You got me.
제대로 걸렸네
You've been avoiding her
ever since we started going out.
처음부터 피하기만 했어
난 재니스 좋아하려고
무지 노력했다
I made an effort to like Janice.
Now I think it's your turn to make an effort
to like Kathy by going out with us. Right?
같이 저녁 먹으면서 최소한의
성의라도 보여 봐, 알았어?
-Yeah, right.
-Good. And hey, my treat.
- 그래, 알았어
- 좋아, 내가 살게
-Only because you're not eating, right?
-Right.
- 배부르다니까 사는 거야, 어?
- 그럼요
죄송해요, 할머니
Sorry, Grandma.
Ross isn't here.
오빠 없다
오... 됐어!
Stop it!
I'll see you at the party?
그럼 파티에서 봐요
Beer's fear, man!
Twenty-four, seven!
밤새도록 엉망으로 취해보세!
I am so gonna marry that guy.
쟤랑 결혼할까 봐
What?
뭐?
-I think he's stealing from me.
-Why?
도둑맞은 기분이야
- 왜?
- 도둑맞았으니까
Because he's stealing from me!
Hi, it's me...
나 왔어, 수프랑
...and soup.
I just saw Josh. He looked so
yummy in your leather jacket.
조시는 네 가죽재킷 입히니까
엄청 귀엽더라
I don't eat chicken,
so it's just noodle soup.
여기, 난 치킨 안 먹거든
그냥 면발 수프야
There's no chicken in the broth,
so it's really just noodle water.
건더기는 없으니까
맹탕 우동이라고 생각해
-Thank you so much.
-Sure.
고맙다, 피비
What are you doing?
그걸로 뭐하게?
I need your germs.
I want my cold back.
감기 걸리려면
네 병균이 필요해
I miss my sexy voice.
내 섹시한 목소리 돌려줘
Sorry, Phoebe.
미안하다
It's okay.
괜찮아
How's the soup?
수프 어때?
우엑!
Check it out!
You can see that girl's underwear.
세상에, 저 여자 속옷 보여요
Is she great, or what?
경이로운 여성이지?
What do you think?
자, 어때요?
She's not really my type.
- 내 타입이 아니군요
- 저렇게 예쁜데?
Not your type?
She's gorgeous.
You know what it is?
The fishnet stockings.
망사스타킹 때문이에요
망사스타킹을 보면 아버지가
신던 망사스타킹이 생각나서
Whenever I see a girl in fishnet
stockings, it reminds me of...
...my father in fishnet stockings.
Understanding a little more of
why you're single.
왜 아직 싱글인지
짐작이 가네요
I have a friend you'd like. She's really
pretty. And then we could double date.
정말 예쁜 친구가 있는데
더블데이트 어때요
No, thanks.
전 됐어요
I've got some ugly friends, and
they're all available too.
좋아요, 못생긴 친구도
소개시켜 줄 수 있어요
I'm gonna grab a beer.
맥주 가져올게요
I'll be right back.
잠깐 기다려
-What was that?
-What?
이게 뭐야?
왜?
Kathy's being really nice
and you just walked away.
생각해서 그러는데
무안을 주면 어떡해?
What do you want from me?
- 원하는 게 뭐야?
- 캐시를 좋아해 봐
I want you to like her.
If that's too damn difficult for you,
then the least you could do is pretend.
그게 정 힘들면
척이라도 하든지
-I am pretending.
-Then do it better.
- 척하고 있어
- 좀더 노력해 봐
What do you say I go over there and
tell her how much I like her?
내가 캐시를 얼마나
좋아하는지 말해줄까?
I can tell her how much
I've been thinking of her.
아니, 늘 캐시 생각을 하지
처음부터 내 맘에 쏙 들었어
I haven't stopped thinking
about her since we met.
I'm so over the top,
want-to-slit-my-own-throat...
숨넘어가게, 몸살나게
캐시를 사랑하고 있지
...in love with her
that for every minute...
매일, 매시간, 매순간
내가 먼저 만났다는 게
분하고 원통하고 열불난다!
...I can't believe my own damn bad
luck that you met her first!
That's pretty good.
그거 아주 좋다
But you might want
to tone it down a little.
약간만 부드럽게 해봐
I still have a fever? Are you
sure that thing's working right?
아직 열이 있어?
고장 난 거 아냐?
Well, we could take
it the other way.
고장 난 건 너야
아만다가 집 앞에 내려줬어
So Amanda just dropped me off.
That's one of the things
I love about her.
아만다는 나이가 지긋해서
운전면허증도 있잖아?
She's old enough to drive.
You're not going
to Mom and Dad's tonight?
아버지한테 못 가겠구나
No, sorry.
- 그래, 미안해
- 아만다 어디 있어?
Where's Amanda?
- 레이첼, 약 좀 줘
- 같이 가지 그래?
Could you get me
some cough drops?
I'm thinking you could bring her...
...and you guys could go up to your
old room and not make out.
어릴 적 쓰던 방에 가서
실컷 헛물이나 켜봐
Cough drop, please?
오빠, 약 좀 줄래?
At least she's not
going out with me...
최소한 아만다는 날 팔아서
성인영화관에 들어가진 않아
...to get into R-rated movies.
Why don't you just marry her?
결혼하시든지, 참! 그러고 보니
아만다는 레즈비언이 아니네?
Wait, you can't! I forgot.
She's not a lesbian.
-Amanda and I have a
-You have nothing!
- 이봐, 우리는...
- 있긴 뭐가 있어!
애 봐주는 주제에
데이트는 무슨!
You're not even going out!
You're her babysitter.
12살짜리나 하는 일을
You have a 12-year-old girl's job!
조의를 표하옵니다
That is so sad.
남자친구한테 털리고 다니는
주제에 웃음씩이나 나오겠다
And what are you laughing at,
Miss My-keg-sucking-boyfriend...
...-is-stealing-from-me?
So he stole a couple bucks
from me. Big deal!
고작 몇 달러 훔친 거야
이걸 사줬다니까
At least he got me
something with it.
That's mine!
그건 내 거야!
Would you both please
start acting like adults?
제발 두 사람
철 좀 들어라
And give me my cough drops!
약이나 대령해!
-Fine.
-Sorry.
- 알았어
- 미안해
Here.
- 여기
- 고마워
Thank you.
At least I made $10 in
my relationship.
그래도 난 10달러 벌었네요
You know...?
너...
Parading goats are parading
염소 부대가 행진하네
거리를 따라 행진하네
Parading down the street
Parading goats are parading
염소 부대가 행진하네
꽤 맛난 걸 뒤로하고
Leaving little treats
Does it even work
without my sexy voice?
목소리가 바뀌니까
영 맛이 안 나요
I like it.
좋은데 뭐
-Gunther, kiss me.
-What?
우리 키스해요
뭐?
Do it, deputy!
Do something!
야!
We aren't exactly sleeping in here,
but do you mind?
자는 건 아니지만
신경 좀 써라
Can I sleep on your couch?
소파 좀 써도 될까?
난 아직 종이반죽남자를
기다리는 중이에요
And I'm still waiting
For my papier-mache man
Thank you, my babies.
감사합니다, 여러분
Rachel?
- 레이첼?
- 네
피비하고 무슨 일이
있었는지 들었어?
Did you hear what happened
between me and Phoebe?
아뇨
키스했어, 내가 시작한 건
아니지만 멈출 수가 없었어
We kissed. I didn't initiate it,
but I also didn't stop it.
I've been feeling guilty.
죄책감이 들어서
그렇군요
Okay.
So...
어때... 우리 이상 없지?
...are we cool?
Okay.
그럼요
I knew you would understand.
이해해 줄지 알았어